Good Fight: The Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War: Audiotapes ALBA.AUDIO.216
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The Good Fight: The Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War: Audiotapes
circa 1980-1983
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sills, Sam
ALBA.AUDIO.216
12 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 1 CD box, 5 cassette boxes, and 1 custom box
Scope and Contents
"The Good Fight," the 1983 feature-length documentary, pays homage to American volunteers who served with the International Brigades during the Spanish Civil War. The film makes extensive use of archival footage from the war, stills, primary documents, radio broadcasts, newsreels, and interviews. The collection includes 247 reel-to-reel tapes of "pre-interview" with volunteers, most of whom were later interviewed on film. Consult archivist regarding the associated manuscript, film and photographic collection.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Access copies of sound recordings may be available by appointment for reading room listening only. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
- Frank, Alexander, undated (Box 1, Cd 341-343)
- O'Reilly, Salaria Kea, undated (Box 1, Cd 310-311)
- Pappas, Nick, undated (Box 1, Cd 116-118)
- Unprocessed Audiocassettes, circa 1980-1983
  - Art Munday, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_355, 216_356)
  - Tony DeMaio, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_356, 216_357)
  - Carl Marzoni, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_358, 216_359)
  - Vaughn Love, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_360, 216_361, Box 10, Audiocassette 216_340)
  - Sam Gonshak, 1981 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_362, 216_363)
  - Paul Burns, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_364, 216_365)
  - Patrick Roosevelt, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_366, 216_368)
  - Thomas Page, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_367, 216_369, 216_370, Box 10, Audiocassette 216_336)
  - Charlie Nusser, 1980 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_371, 216_372)
  - Weissman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_373)
  - Hemingway, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_373)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project Music Ideas -- Cassette 2, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_374)
  - The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project -- Cassette 1, 4, 5, 6, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_375, 216_386, 216_387, 216_388)
  - Music -- Abraham Lincoln Brigade, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_376,)
  - Al Toca Piańa, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_377)
  - Will Roger Jr. -- 2nd Take, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_378)
  - "As It Happens" CBC Radio, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_379)
  - Hellerman: "The Internationale", circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_380)
  - Saint Saens Marche Heroique, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_381)
  - "They Shall Not Pass", circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_382)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project -- Music Session 1, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_383)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Film Project -- Studio Session 2, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_384)
  - Music 3 Abraham Lincoln Brigade Project, 1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_385)
  - George Watt, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_389)
  - Ben Holtzman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 11, Audiocassette 216_389, 216_390)
  - Joe Hautaniemi, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_248, 216_249)
  - George Brodsky, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_249, 216_250)
  - Dartmouth History Panel, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_251)
  - Ben Iceland, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_252, 216_253)
  - Jimmy Yates, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_254, 216_255)
  - Matti Mattson, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_256, 216_257)
  - Harry Fisher and John Rody, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_257, 216_258, 216_259)
  - Tom Lloyd, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_259, 216_260)
  - Charles O'Flanerty, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_261, 216_262)
  - Don MacCleod, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_263, 216_264)
  - Alvah Bessie, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_264, 216_265)
  - Milt Wolff, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_265, 216_266, 216_267)
  - Ester Silverstein Blanc, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_267, 216_268, 216_393)
  - Bill Sennett, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_269, 216_270)
  - Earl Vail, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_170, 216_271)
  - Luchell McDaniel, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_271, 216_272)
  - Bill McCarthy, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_273, 216_274)
  - Ben Sills, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_275, 216_276, 216_277)
  - Bill Bailey, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_277, 216_278, 216_279, 216_280)
  - George Kaye, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_280, 216_281)
  - Howard Goddard, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_281, 216_282)
  - Seema Matlin Goddard, circa 1980-1983 (Box 8, Audiocassette 216_282)
  - Mary Rolfe, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_283)
  - Archie Brown, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_284)
  - Curly Mende, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_285)
  - Mildred Rackley Simon, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_286, 216_287)
  - Ed Bender, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_287)
  - Hilda Bell Roberts, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_288, 216_289)
  - Ruth Davidow, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_289, 216_290)
  - Dave Thompson, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_291, 216_292)
  - Rudy Corbin, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_292, 216_293)
  - Becky Durem, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_294)
  - Gabriel "Jack" Quiñones, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_295)
  - Manny Harriman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_296, 216_297)
  - Irving Mitchel, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_297, 216_298)
  - Ken Shaker, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_299, 216_300)
  - Bill Wheeler, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_301)
  - Jack Hartzman and May Hartzman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_302)
  - Irving Frankel, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_303)
  - Sid Kaufman and Duncan Keir, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_304, 216_305)
  - Edna Romer, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_306)
  - Robert Colodny, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_307, 216_308)
  - Lou Bortz, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_309)
  - Salaria Kea O'Reilly, circa 1980-1983; cuid36858 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_310, 216_311)
  - Pat O'Reilly, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_311)
  - Morris Stamm, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_312)
  - Admiral "Kil" Kilpatrick, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_313)
  - Milt Cohen, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_314)
  - Sidney Narris, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_315, 216_316)
  - John Rossen, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_316, 216_317)
  - Joe Zanadowski and Paul Lutka, circa 1980-1983 (Box 9, Audiocassette 216_318)
  - Alex Weinerman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_319)
  - Ralph Thornton, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_319)
  - Bob Taylor, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_320, 216_321)
  - Marion Noble, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_321, 216_322)
  - Saul Wellman, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_323, 216_324)
  - Sid Linn, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_325)
  - Rose Sorkin and Michael Shantzek, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_326, 216_327)
  - Robert Gladnick, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_327, 216_328, 216_329)
  - Ed Lending, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_329, 216_330, 216_331)
  - Bob Reed, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_332, 216_333)
  - Albert Edward Chisholm, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_333, 216_334, 216_335, 216_336)
  - Elias Schultz, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_337)
  - James Crooks, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_338)
  - Robert Ingalls and Brooke Carmichael, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_339, 216_341)
  - Frank Alexander, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_340, 216_350, 216_341, 216_342, 216_343)
  - Max Farrar, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_344, 216_345)
  - Irving Gold, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_346)
  - Joseph Azar, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_346, 216_347)
  - Lini DeVries, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_347, 216_348)
  - Bill Miller, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_349, 216_351)
  - Toby Jensky, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_351)
  - Tedd Cogswell, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_352, 216_353)
  - Leonard Levenson, circa 1980-1983 (Box 10, Audiocassette 216_353, 216_254)
  - Maury Colow, circa 1980-1983 (Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 216_391, 216_392)
  - B. Colow, circa 1980-1983 (Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 216_392)